jobsdb.com.ph 2014-11-05

# Privacy Policy | jobsDB Philippines

jobsDB Philippines complies with the requirements of the Electronic Commerce Act of the Philippines, the Data Privacy Act of the Philippines, and the prescribed guidelines for the protection of personal information and data in information and communications systems. In doing so, jobsDB Philippines will ensure compliance by its staff to the strictest standards of security and confidentiality in respect of all personal information and data submitted by users via the Site and jobsDB Philippines will not, subject to the terms herein, release such information to anyone without the prior consent of the relevant user(s) of the Site (whether registered or not) (“ **User(s)** ”).

Users are strongly recommended to read this privacy statement ( **“Privacy Statement”** ) carefully to have an understanding of jobsDB Philippines’s policy and practices with regard to the treatment of personal information and data provided by Users on the Site. This Privacy Statement is applicable to both registered and unregistered Users, and the terms herein may be updated, revised, varied and/or amended from time to time as jobsDB Philippines may deem necessary and/or appropriate.

By registering for or using the services/Site, or by clicking the ‘Register’ button, User:

(a) | 

consent to jobsDB Philippines and/or jobsDB Philippines’s group companies collecting, using, disclosing and/or processing User’s personal data for the purposes as described below;  
  
---|---  
(b) | 

consent to jobsDB Philippines and/or jobsDB Philippines’s group companies disclosing Users’ personal data to jobsDB Philippines’s and/or jobsDB Philippines’s group companies’ third party service providers or agents (whether within or outside the Philippines) for the purposes as described below.  
  
If Users have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Statement, they should contact the Customer Service Assistant of jobsDB Philippines’s Customer Service Department, whose contact details are set out under the section headed “ **Enquiries** ” below.

In this Privacy Statement, the following terms shall have the respective meanings specified below unless the context otherwise requires:

“ **Advertiser(s)** ” means user who places a job advertisement or promotes any job related activities via the Site.   
“ **jobsDB** ” means Jobs DB Inc.   
“ **jobsDB Philippines** ” means Jobs DB Philippines Inc.   
“ **Job Seeker(s)** ” means users seeking employment.   
“ **Site** ” means any website, job portal or mobile application owned and operated by jobsDB and its affiliates/subsidiaries. 

**Purpose of Collection of Personal Data**

In the course of using the Site, Users may disclose or be asked to provide personal information and/or data. In order to have the benefit of and enjoy various services offered by the Site, it may be necessary for Users to provide jobsDB Philippines with their personal information and/or data. Although Users are not obliged to provide the information and/or data as requested on the Site, jobsDB Philippines will not be able to render certain services on the Site in the event that Users fail to do so.

jobsDB Philippines’s purposes for collecting and using the information and data on the Site include but are not limited to the following:

a) | for the daily operation of the services provided to Users;  
---|---  
b) | 

to assist Job Seekers to find appropriate employment with Employers and to assist Employers to assess the suitability of candidates for job vacancy for a wide spectrum of jobs and industries;  
  
c) | 

to provide Users with various services offered by the Site and newsletters, information on job openings and promotional and marketing materials (for further details, please refer to section headed “ **Subscription of Newsletter/Promotional Materials/Marketing Materials** ” below);  
  
d) | 

to handle and follow up on enquiries, requests and complaints from Users;  
  
e) | 

to contact Users regarding administrative notices and communications relevant to his/her use of the Site and to respond to Users’ inquiries or requests;  
  
f) | 

to assist jobsDB Philippines with developments for future marketing and promoting purposes or other internal purposes;  
  
g) | 

to verify the identity of Users who have posted advertisements, materials, representations, messages, views or comments or such other information (collectively “ **Information** “) on the Site;  
  
h) | 

to identify Users who have viewed the Information posted on the Site;  
  
i) | 

to allow Users to enjoy their benefits as members of the Site by enrolling for special events and promotions hosted by jobsDB Philippines and/or its affiliates and/or partner company;  
  
j) | 

to identify Users who have enjoyed their benefits as members of the Site by receiving and using marketing promotional materials;  
  
k) | 

to facilitate jobsDB Philippines and/or its affiliates to use the Users’ personal data for the purposes relating to the provision of services offered by jobsDB Philippines and marketing services and/or special event of jobsDB Philippines and/or its affiliates;  
  
l) | 

to obtain statistics about Users to analyze usage of the Site in order to help its further development; and  
  
m) | 

for purposes other than the above mentioned which are related to jobsDB Philippines’s and/or its affiliates’ provision of their product and/or services.  
  
Before using the Site or disclosing any information or data on the Site, Users under the age of 21 should seek prior consent from a person with parental responsibility for him/her, e.g. parent or guardian, who may contact the responsible Customer Service Assistant whose contact details are set out under the section headed “ **Enquiries** ” for registering the User as member of the Site.

jobsDB Philippines strives to only collect personal data which are necessary and adequate but not excessive in relation to the purposes set out hereinabove.

If jobsDB Philippines requires the use of your personal data for a purpose other than those set out hereinabove, we will request your prescribed consent to the same. If you are a minor, the prescribed consent should be given by your parent or guardian.

**Collection of Personal Data**

jobsDB Philippines may collect personal information and/or data about a User such as his/her name, log-in ID and password, address, email address, phone number, age, gender, date of birth, country of residence, nationality, education level and work experience that is/are not otherwise publicly available. Occasionally, jobsDB Philippines may also collect additional personal information and/or data from a User in connection with contests, surveys, or special offers.

Only duly authorized staff of jobsDB Philippines will be permitted to access Users’ personal information and data, and jobsDB Philippines shall not release such personal information and data to any third parties save and except for the circumstances listed below under the section headed “ **Disclosure or Transfer of Data** ”.

**Disclosure or Transfer of Data**

jobsDB Philippines agrees to take all practicable steps to keep all personal information and data of Users confidential and/or undisclosed, subject to the following.

Generally speaking, jobsDB Philippines will only disclose and/or transfer Users’ personal information and/or data to jobsDB Philippines’s personnel and staff for the purpose of providing services to Users and corporate clients of jobsDB Philippines who have made specific requests for such information and/or data with Users’ prior consent. However, jobsDB Philippines may disclose and/or transfer such information and/or data to third parties under the following circumstances:

a) | where the information and/or data is to be disclosed and/or transferred to any third party suppliers or external service providers who have been duly authorized by jobsDB Philippines to use such information and/or data and who will facilitate the services on the Site, under a duty of confidentiality;  
---|---  
b) | 

where the information and/or data is disclosed and/or transferred to any agents, affiliates or associates of jobsDB Philippines who have been duly authorized by jobsDB Philippines to use such information and/or data;  
  
c) | 

where permitted under the “ **[Terms and Conditions](http://ph.jobsdb.com/en-ph/pages/terms/terms-conditions)** ”;  
  
d) | 

where jobsDB Philippines needs to protect and defend its rights and property;  
  
e) | 

where jobsDB Philippines considers necessary to do so in order to comply with the applicable laws and regulations, including without limitation compliance with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on the Site;  
  
f) | 

where jobsDB Philippines deems necessary in order to deliver the products and services that we offer and cultivate a positive user experience; and/or  
  
g) | 

where jobsDB Philippines deems necessary in order to maintain and/or improve the services on the Site.  
  
Personal data collected via the Site may be transferred, stored and processed in any country in which jobsDB Philippines or its affiliates operate. By using the Site, Users are deemed to have agreed to, consented to and authorized jobsDB Philippines to disclose and/or transfer their personal information and data under the circumstances stated above, as well as to any transfer of information (including the Information) outside of the Users’ country.

**Subscription of Newsletter/Promotional Materials/Marketing Materials  **

jobsDB Philippines and its affiliates may from time to time send to members and Users of the Site newsletters, information on job openings, and marketing materials based on the personal information and data that they have provided to jobsDB Philippines. jobsDB Philippines may use Users’ data in direct marketing and jobsDB Philippines requires the Users’ consent (which includes an indication of no objection) for that purpose. In this connection, please note that:

a) | 

the name, log-in ID and password, contact details, age, gender, date of birth, country of residence, nationality, education level and work experience of Users held by jobsDB Philippines from time to time may be used by jobsDB Philippines and/or its authorized personnel or staff in direct marketing;  
  
---|---  
b) | 

the following classes of services, products and subjects may be marketed:

| i. | travelling related products and services;  
---|---  
ii. | job-hunting and agencies services offered other than by jobsDB Philippines;  
iii. | various courses and programs for Users seeking jobs and career opportunities;  
iv. | special events hosted by jobsDB Philippines and its affiliates for members and Users, including but not limited to courses, workshops, and competitions;  
v. | reward, loyalty or privilege programs and related products and services;  
vi. | special offers including coupons, discounts, group purchase offers and promotional campaigns;  
vii. | products and services offered by jobsDB Philippines’s affiliates and advertisers (the names of such affiliates and advertisers can be found in the application form(s) for the relevant products and services, as the case may be);  
viii. | donations and contributions for charitable and/or non-profit making purposes;  
c) | 

the above products, services and subjects may be provided or (in the case of donations and contributions) solicited by jobsDB Philippines and/or;

| i. | jobsDB Philippines’s affiliates;  
---|---  
ii. | third party service providers providing the products, services and subjects listed in paragraph (b) above; and  
iii. | charitable or non-profit making organizations;  
d) | 

in addition to marketing the above services, products, and subject itself, jobsDB Philippines also intends to provide the data described in paragraph (a) above to all or any of the persons described in paragraph (c) above for use by them in marketing those services, products and subjects, and jobsDB Philippines requires the Users’ written consent (which includes an indication of no objection) for that purpose; and  
  
e) | 

jobsDB Philippines may receive money or other property in return for providing the data to the other persons in paragraph (d) above and, when requesting the Users’ written consent as described in paragraph (d) above, jobsDB Philippines will inform Users if jobsDB Philippines receives any money or other property in return for providing the data to other persons.  

In this regard, Users may choose to sign up or unsubscribe for such materials by logging into the registration or Users’ account maintenance webpage, or clicking on the automatic link appearing in each newsletter/message or contact the Customer Service Assistant of jobsDB Philippines, whose contact details are set out under the section headed “ **Enquiries** ”.

 **Access to or request for correction of data**

Any User is entitled to request access to or make amendments to his/her own personal information and data kept with jobsDB Philippines by contacting the Customer Service Assistant of jobsDB Philippines’s Customer Service Department at whose contact details are set out under the section headed “ **Enquiries** ”. Subject to the paragraph below, User may alternatively edit, amend or delete his/her personal information and data at any time by logging into the “ **My jobsDB** ” section of the Site.

In the event that a User wishes to access or amend his/her personal information and data, jobsDB Philippines may request him/her to provide personal details in order to verify his/her identity. Identity card number or passport number or company registration number cannot be amended unless such data is proved to be inaccurate. jobsDB Philippines is required to respond to a User’s request within 40 days of his/her request and will endeavor to do so wherever possible, but jobsDB Philippines reserves the rights to charge the User a reasonable fee for doing so.

 **Cookies and Log Files**

jobsDB Philippines does not collect any personally identifiable information from any Users while they visit and browse the Site. When Users access the Site, jobsDB Philippines records their visits only and does not collect their personal information or data. The Site’s server software will also record the domain name, server, address and track the pages Users visit and store such information in “cookies”, and gather and store information such as internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data in log files. All these are done without the Users being aware that they are occurring.

Users can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but Users can modify their individual browser settings to decline cookies if they prefer. However, Users should note that disabling cookies on their browser may prevent them from taking full advantage of the Site.

jobsDB Philippines does not link the information and data automatically collected in the above manner to any personally identifiable information. jobsDB Philippines generally uses such automatically collected information and data to estimate the audience size of the Site, gauge the popularity of various parts of the Site, track Users’ movements and number of entries in jobsDB Philippines’s promotional activities and special events, measure Users’ traffic patterns and administer the Site. Such automatically collected information and data will not be disclosed save and except in accordance with the section headed “ **Disclosure or Transfer of Data** ”.

In addition, our third party advertising companies may place cookies on some of the pages Users visit on the Site. These cookies are designed to collect non-personally identifiable information in order to analyze Users’ interests and searches on our Site to help deliver more relevant advertisements when Users visit our Site and other websites. The non-personally identifiable information collected by these cookies may be shared with other third parties for purpose of managing and targeting advertisements and for market research analysis.

 **Links to Other Websites  **

The Site may provide links to other websites which are not owned or controlled by jobsDB, jobsDB Philippines or its affiliates. Personal information and data from Users may be collected on these other websites when Users visit such websites and make use of the services provided therein. Where and when Users decide to click on any advertisement or hyperlink on the Site which grants Users access to another website, the protection of Users’ personal information and data which are deemed to be private and confidential may be exposed in these other websites.

Non-registered Users who gain access to the Site via their accounts in online social networking tools (including but not limited to Facebook, Twitter and Sina Weibo) are deemed to have consented to the terms of this Privacy Statement, and such Users’ personal data which they have provided to those networking tools may be obtained by jobsDB Philippines and be used by jobsDB Philippines and its authorized persons in and outside of the User’s country for the purpose of providing services and marketing materials to the Users. jobsDB Philippines and its authorized personnel may gain access and use the personal data of such Users so obtained, subject to the other provisions of this Privacy Statement.

This Privacy Statement is only applicable to the Site. Users are reminded that this Privacy Statement grants no protection to Users’ personal information and data that may be exposed on websites other than the Site, and jobsDB Philippines is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites. Users are strongly recommended to refer to the privacy policies of such other websites before using those websites.

**Testimonials**

jobsDB Philippines posts Users’ testimonials on the Site, which may contain personally identifiable information such as the Users’ names. jobsDB Philippines does obtain the Users’ consent prior to posting the testimonials to post their names along with their testimonials.

**Security**

The security of Users’ personal information and data is important to jobsDB Philippines. jobsDB Philippines will always strive to ensure that Users’ personal information and data will be protected against unauthorized access. jobsDB Philippines has implemented appropriate electronic and managerial measures in order to safeguard, protect and secure Users’ personal information and data.

All personal information and data provided by Users are only accessible by the authorized personnel of jobsDB Philippines or its authorized third parties, and such personnel shall be instructed to observe the terms of this Privacy Statement when accessing such personal information and data. Users may rest assured that their personal information and data will only be kept for as long as is necessary to fulfill the purpose for which it is collected. Registered User should safeguard his/her unique Username and Password by keeping it secret and confidential and never share these details with anyone.

jobsDB Philippines uses a third party service provider to facilitate the electronic payment transactions on the Site.

jobsDB Philippines follows generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information and data submitted by Users to the Site, both during transmission and once jobsDB Philippines receives it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while jobsDB Philippines strives to protect Users’ personal information and data against unauthorized access, jobsDB Philippines cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**  
Retention of Personal Data  **

Once jobsDB Philippines has obtained a User’s personal information and/or data, it will be maintained securely in jobsDB Philippines’s system for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the data was collected as set out under the section headed “ **Purpose of Collection of Personal Data** ”. Once registered, Users may terminate his/her membership of the Site by contacting the Customer Service Assistant of jobsDB Philippines’s Customer Service Department at whose contact details are set out under the section headed “ **Enquiries** ”. jobsDB Philippines may retain User’s personal information even after User has closed his/her account if retention is reasonably necessary to comply with our legal obligations, meet regulatory requirements, resolve disputes between Users, prevent fraud and abuse, or enforce this Privacy Statement and the **[Terms and Conditions](http://ph.jobsdb.com/en-ph/pages/terms/terms-conditions)**.

**  
Changes in this Privacy Statement **

jobsDB Philippines reserves the right to update, revise, modify or amend this Privacy Statement at any time as jobsDB Philippines deems necessary, so Users are strongly recommended to review this Privacy Statement frequently. If jobsDB Philippines decides to update, revise, modify or amend this Privacy Statement, jobsDB Philippines will post those changes to this webpage and/or other places as jobsDB Philippines deems appropriate, so that Users will be aware of what information jobsDB Philippines collects, how jobsDB Philippines uses it, and under what circumstances, if any, jobsDB Philippines discloses it. **  
**

If jobsDB Philippines makes material changes to this Privacy Statement, jobsDB Philippines will notify Users on this webpage, by email, or by means of a notice on the home page of jobsDB Philippines.

Such changes to this Privacy Statement shall apply from the time that jobsDB Philippines posts the same on this webpage. Users’ continued use of the Site and services on the Site shall constitute acceptance of the changes to this Privacy Statement.

**Enquiries**

Should you have any enquiries relating to this Privacy Statement, please email at cs@jobsdb.com.ph, telephone at +63 2 914 8000 or write to us at the following address:

jobsDB Philippines   
Suite 905-907, Taipan Place,  
F. Ortigas Jr. Road, Ortigas Center,  
Pasig City, Philippines 1605
